What are you doing, Dobato?
I'm making decorations out of this pretty paper!
Wait, that's the paper the landlady bought.
Yeah, Chitose bought it at the gift shop downtown. She said to give it to everyone at Yomogi Nursery.
I'll make plenty of these and decorate the windows and doors!
Everyone will be so happy!
No, they'll just be irritated.
Lemme tell you something.
That's origami paper.
You're supposed to fold it.
What do I do, Ioryogi!?
I can't change it back!
Ioryogi...
You're such a cut-up.
There ain't no putting it back together!
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
... Secret Wish.
All right.
Thanks.
Miss Sayaka, you don't look quite right.
You look worn out.
Come on.
You don't tell women they look worn out.
You'll hurt their feelings.
I'm not joking around!
I'm bringing this to the office now.
Thanks.
Um, Miss Sayaka...
Oh, Kobato?
I'm sorry!
What's wrong?
Chitose said this was for everyone at Yomogi!
Oh, origami paper!
There's so much of it!
There used to be even more...
I didn't know origami paper was for folding, and kinda messed up...
I'm so sorry!
Miss Sayaka!
Miss Sayaka! Miss Sayaka!!!
Fujimoto! Fujimoto!!!
What?
It's Miss Sayaka!
I'm fine.
Let's get you to the hospital.
I said I'm fine.
There's no way you're fine!
I am. Just let me rest a little and I'll be fine.
I know a doctor!
I'll go get him!
Kobato?
Kobato! Where are you going?
Excuse me!
Excuse me! Please come to the door!
Please come to the door!
Kobato?
What's wrong?
Where's Shuichiro?
Help me! Miss Sayaka is-!
Please!
What's wrong with Miss Sayaka?
You don't need to worry.
What's the diagnosis?
Exhaustion from lack of sleep, complicated by a minor case of gastritis.
I see.
I'll write a prescription.
Once she gets some rest, feed her something easy on the stomach.
Okay.
Sorry to call you so suddenly.
No, I enjoy a change of pace sometimes.
Excuse me!
Will Miss Sayaka be okay?
If she keeps this up, next time will be worse than just collapsing.
I want you to tell her not to just write it off as exhaustion.
Okay.
Take care.
Thank you.
How do you know him?
He lives with Kohaku.
Kohaku?
Oh, that lady from before?
Yes...
What's wrong?
Is Miss Sayaka sick?
She's fine.
Really?
Yeah. The doctor said she'll get better soon.
If you don't cheer up, she'll be worried.
Let's sing so she gets better.
Yeah!
Under the blue, blue sky
Kobato completely forgot about me.
Outside in the...
Hey.
Yeah?
Do you think just sitting here watching will make her better?
I just want to stay a little longer...
Grow up.
You should be looking after the kids.
That would let her rest easy.
You're right.
So, how is she?
She's resting.
I see.
That's nice.
See, if you do this-
A servant!
Oh, so that's how you make origami.
Look, Kobato!
Oh, a balloon!
What are you making, Toshihiko?
Cranes!
Cranes?
They're a bird.
Oh, I see, a bird.
You're making a lot of them.
A thousand!
Eh? A thousand!?
Yeah. That way Miss Sayaka will get better soon.
If you fold a thousand cranes, it cures someone.
Toshihiko!
Teach me how to fold cranes!
I'll do it too!
I'll fold cranes!
Me too!
Let's all fold them!
Like this?
Yeah, like that.
Huh?
This is hard.
How about this?
I made one!
Me too!
Show me how!
I wonder if Kobato will be okay.
Aren't you worrying about the wrong person?
Yeah, you're right.
But...
For some reason I'm worried about her.
Will Miss Sayaka be better tomorrow?
She'll be fine!
After all, we folded a thousand cranes.
Yeah!
I'll be back from work as soon as I can.
Take care of Miss Sayaka.
Okay...
Call me if anything happens.
Boss, I need to ask you a favor.
What is it this time?
Can I have fewer hours for a while?
Don't you need the money?
Yeah, but right now there's something more important.
I understand.
Keep in mind, when you have spare time again I'm gonna work you even harder.
I'm sorry. Thanks.
Miss Sayaka...
Kobato?
Have you been here this whole time?
Yeah...
How are the kids?
Everyone's already gone home.
That's good.
Sorry to make you worry.
Please, rest more!
And here I was trying to cheer you up.
I never thought I'd feel relieved leaving things to you and Fujimoto.
If anything happens to me...
Why are you saying that!?
That... That's...
If anything happens to you...
Everyone...
We'd be so sad!
So don't say that!
Kobato...
That's enough for today. Go home.
You're enough of an airhead at the best of times, we can't have you keeping her up.
An airhead!?
I am not!
I'll take over, you can go home.
Okay...
Try not to space out.
I told you, I'm not-
Just go.
You got chewed out?
It's his way of saying "good job".
Yeah.
It's just like she said.
All the kids helped fold.
I see.
These are the ones she folded.
They're all like this.
She really is a good girl.
You're that worried about Sayaka?
Hey, Kobato.
Never mind.
Okay...
Could her memories be coming back?
Chiho, what's the answer to number 7?
Eh? You don't know either?
Kobato!
It's Kobato!
Is Chitose here?
Mama went to the neighborhood meeting.
I see...
What's wrong?
You don't look good, Kobato.
Someone's sick!
Oh no, Kobato!
It's not me!
Miss Sayaka is sick!
I want to make something for Miss Sayaka, but I don't know what.
We all made her a thousand cranes, but...
A thousand cranes?
Yeah.
I wasn't that good at making them, though...
What if it doesn't work because mine are no good?
Don't worry, Kobato.
I'm sure it'll be fine.
I hope so...
I know! That!
What, that thing Mama always cooks when someone's sick?
Rice gruel?
Yeah, rice gruel?
That's it, rice gruel!
Mama says rice gruel is easy on the stomach, so it's good when you're sick!
Easy on the stomach?!
Shuichiro mentioned that!
He said to feed Miss Sayaka things that are easy on the stomach!
So let's make her some rice gruel!
Yeah, it'll make her feel better!
Okay! I'll make Miss Sayaka some rice gruel!
But how do I make it?
Let's draw her instructions, Chiho!
Great idea, Chise!
It's like this...
So this is rice gruel?
It's white...
And it's kinda syrupy.
I get it!
Syrupy!
Mama says to be careful when you're eating it or you'll scald yourself!
Steamy hot!
And when you make it...
You put a lot of water in!
Covered with water!
You gonna be okay?
Who's there?
What are you doing!?
I thought I'd make her some rice gruel.
I even got Chiho and Chise to teach me how.
But it didn't turn out that good.
Rice gruel's easy on the stomach, so it'll be good for Miss Sayaka.
After you put in the rice, put in a lot of water.
Then put it on the burner and wait until it boils.
After that, you simmer it.
Come on, how did you even end up with that?
If she had any of it, she'd just get sicker.
Hey, don't cry.
If Miss Sayaka dies...
It'll be okay. People don't die that easily.
Yes they do!
Even little things can kill someone!
Did you have that happen to someone?
It'll be fine.
Miss Sayaka isn't going to die.
It'll be okay.
It's great! I feel a lot better.
Wonderful!
Now I'm worried I'll overeat.
It's tasty.
I'm just glad I could help out.
Well, I did most of the work.
Yeah, but...
But what?
Never mind.
Figured.
It's not like you got any more.
Staring at it like that isn't going to help, either.
I know!
You're a lot less unhappy about it than I expected.
Now that you mention it...
I wonder why.
Since I broke down in front of Fujimoto,
for some reason all the the memories I'd kept locked up are flooding out.
I feel so warm.
What are you doing getting healed when you're supposed to heal people?
Getting healed?
This is...
Good morning.
Good morning!
Morning.
It's Miss Sayaka!
Good morning!
Good morning, Miss Sayaka!
Good morning.
Did you get better?
I'm fine now.
I knew the thousand cranes would work.
Good morning, Kobato!
Good morning!
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you tell me "thanks", if you say "thanks" and smile
Going back and forth, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
... Mysterious Life-form.
Next episode